What are you doing out here?
Listening to the sound of the waves.
You were just listening?
Not looking?
Because...
I can't see them, right?
Then why not come during the day?
I'd rather do that.
But they'd find me if I did.
More importantly, who are you?
I don't think we've met.
I was just brought here recently.
Some stuff happened, you see.
I see.
What's your name?
The grown-ups call me #602.
Nagisa.
Since you love the sea,
that's what I'll call you.
What's your name?
I don't have a name.
But...
What?
I have a code name, I guess.
EPISODE 1: TO SEE YOU ONCE MORE
Where am I?
What was that for, Natsunagi?
That's my line!
Don't try to kiss your classmate
when she's asleep!
This isn't fair.
You two are being very loud.
Saikawa?
What are you doing here?
Hmm? You want to know why
I'm sleeping next to you, Kimizuka-san?
You're asking me?
Why are you saying it like that?
I didn't bring you here, did I?
You really don't remember?
Char?!
We were going to visit Ma'am's grave when
someone kidnapped us and brought us here.
That's right!
Yes, that's right.
Hmph. You guys are so quick
to let your guard down.
You were kidnapped too, right?
Jeez! Fine! I'm sorry!
If you're seeing this video, it means...
that Kimizuka Kimihiko,
Natsunagi Nagisa,
Saikawa Yui,
and Charlotte Arisaka Anderson
are all in the room.
Siesta—
Ma'am!
It's been a while, Char.
But I'm sorry.
I recorded this video a year ago,
knowing this day would come.
Ma'am...
So this is Siesta-san?
Now, there's a reason I brought you all here.
It's about time you learn...
what happened to me a year ago.
What happened?
I want you to see what happened to us...
and the truth of my death.
And then...
I want you to decide.
And thus began a retelling of
the three years I spent with Siesta.
We met 10,000 meters above the surface
of the Earth aboard a hijacked airplane
and embarked on a series
of incredible adventures.
And then, as we battled
the secret organization SPES,
we met a strange girl named Alicia.
But there was a personality inside her,
"Hel," that even she didn't know about.
And then we headed to the enemy's hideout,
to follow Hel, or perhaps save Alicia.
There we met Seed, the enemy's leader.
And Siesta began
her final battle with Hel.
What happened on that island,
one year ago?
Why is the detective already dead?
They...
She... learned.
The one who took Siesta's life
on that day, in that place...
It was me.
I killed Siesta-san...
I took the person you cared for most...
I'm sorry.
No, you didn't do anything.
It wasn't you...
It was another...
I didn't just get a heart transplant.
I stole Siesta-san's heart.
And the memories of my youth
and all that time in the hospital...
were because of the memories
from that time at SPES...
Natsunagi learned everything.
She remembered.
Alicia and the girl
called Hel were both her.
You lost your memories
because of that pollen?
Both Nagisa and Kimizuka were affected?
You remembered the whole time, right, Char?
Yes...
Char-san, I...
Don't say a word.
I know it's not your fault.
But... I still want a little more time.
Right.
Everything's okay.
Let's calm down.
We can clasp our hands.
Rotate our shoulders.
Breathe rhythmically.
Close our eyes,
take a deep breath in, then out.
Help our blood flow.
Open our eyes,
and watch our blurry vision clear.
Saikawa...
And when we've done that,
why don't we all have some tea?
Sheesh...
Why are you the most grown-up of us all?
A tea party? That sounds wonderful.
I hope you'll allow me to join.
The next time you try to touch this body,
I'll shatter every bone in yours.
That's not fair...
You're...
Siesta?
Unfortunately, I don't have any tea cakes.
Shall we have some delivered?
Kimihiko will pay.
Hey, don't be so mean to me.
So, where have we been brought?
This is one of Siesta-sama's hideouts.
First I'm hearing of it...
You really do look just like Ma'am...
Charlotte, I'll say this again.
I'm just a robot.
A bio-android created from a portion
of Siesta-sama's body, memories,
and abilities before her death.
The name she gave me was "Noches."
It's hard to believe,
but I guess I have to.
The real one would've let me rest
on her lap instead of flipping me.
I have queried my database,
and it appears that statement is false.
Don't make it so obvious
you're looking away.
And if you're modeled on Siesta,
then stop hating me.
I dislike you because
I'm modeled on Siesta-sama.
I told you not to be so mean to me.
Why does it sound like the two of them
have been married for years?
Yui, don't compare them to a couple.
They're more like a veteran comedy duo.
Listen, Noches.
I understand that you're
the one who kidnapped us.
Which means you needed
to talk to us, right?
Siesta-sama made many preparations
before that day.
And I was given the duty
of telling you the truth.
Nagisa.
It's because of you
that Siesta-sama's will can be carried on.
Ensuring that you survive
and attend school
was her last wish
and the last job she gave me.
So on her behalf, I say...
Thank you.
I...
Why are you telling us about the past now?
Why hide the truth until now?
There are several reasons.
The first being that Siesta-sama
required a long period of time
to suppress the evil "Hel" personality
within Nagisa's body
and stabilize Nagisa herself.
And the second reason
was that she was waiting
for the four of you
to truly come together.
And the last reason is...
Seed.
Seed has taken no overt actions
over the course of the last year.
But it seems that's changed recently.
Stopping them is your job, Nagisa.
My job?
It's not just Natsunagi's problem, right?
That is correct.
But her role is far greater
than yours, Yui's, or Charlotte's.
Because Nagisa is the Great Detective.
That's right.
Siesta-sama didn't tell you yet.
Our "Great Detective" is—
Wait!
Another word and you'll violate
the Federation Charter!
I don't care.
They're a part of this, too.
The Great Detective is one of the Tuners,
the twelve shields
that protect this world.
"Tuners"?
There are dangers that arise
throughout the world at regular intervals,
many at the same time...
And an international organization
has secretly drafted in individuals
to deal with them.
The "Tuners."
There are 12 in all.
They all have different roles.
The "Phantom Thief,"
"the Shrine Maiden," the "Assassin."
It's said that one of them
is even a vampire.
A vampire?
But a year ago, Siesta-sama passed away,
and the role of the "Great Detective"
whose job it is to destroy SPES
became vacant.
It's likely that you, Nagisa, will be
designated the next Great Detective.
Of course, it hasn't been decided yet.
But you have the heart of
the previous Great Detective,
and you carry on her will.
And you can master powers
beyond those of a normal human.
Many people will think that
sufficient reason.
Siesta won't appear
inside her body anymore.
I know.
And so I ask you once more, on her behalf.
Nagisa, will you truly carry on
the will of the Great Detective?
I...
If... just hypothetically,
she were to say yes,
what should she do first?
Hmm...
Let's have her hunt for a mistake.
If Natsunagi is unsure about
becoming the Great Detective,
she can first find a "mistake" in that
footage from a year ago she saw yesterday
and decide then.
That's what Noches said.
Wow, what's with that reaction?
What's going on?
And then she let us go.
But we don't have any clues...
You're kidding me.
You ate lunch all alone, and then
you've been sleeping here ever since?
Lunch tastes better on the roof.
That's not the point.
You would've been spending the night at
school if I hadn't come to get you, right?
Why not make some friends?
It's not that I don't make friends.
It's that I can't.
Well, you can count me, if you want.
On your "friend counter."
Isn't it nice to have somebody
you can talk to about anything?
And she's cute, too!
I've never had a friend,
so I wouldn't know.
You're such a contrarian.
I don't know how you
got along with Siesta-san.
We never really did get along.
We would have a fight
at least  every three days.
Would you be the first
to apologize when it happened?
Most of the time.
But sometimes, I'd get stubborn
and not talk to her for a week.
And then?
She'd start to freak out.
Siesta-san's that cute?
And then when I'd go to talk to her again,
she'd look relieved
for a single instant, and then...
She'd go back to looking upset
and say, "Are you stupid?"
Yup, that's right.
Good work.
You'd get an A grade in Siesta-isms.
You know, you look happy
when you talk about her.
She was all you really wanted, wasn't she?
Don't worry about it.
I was alone before I met her, too.
You're a nice guy.
But it's no good.
Even when I'm talking
to my friends in class,
or when you're trying to cheer me up,
I can't get the sight of it
out of my head.
And it's not just Siesta-san.
I've hurt so many other innocent
people with my own hands...
Sorry to keep you waiting. Huh? Where's Nagi?
She said to leave without her.
So gloomy.
Wh-Wh-Wh-Wh-Wh-What?
Listen to me, Natsunagi.
It's still my turn to be angry.
Huh? This isn't your kink?
I-I-I-I'll kill you twice!
A long time ago...
When I was really down and depressed...
Siesta slapped me on the back.
So I'll always be there
to slap you on the back, too,
and hold your hand.
All you did was run your fingertip
down my back.
You can get as depressed
as you want right now.
You can order takeout
and stress eat as much as you want.
Or curse the unfairness of it all using
as much foul language as you want.
If that still won't wash away your guilt,
then I'll carry half of it.
I couldn't save her then, either.
So the least I can do
is carry some of your pain.
Kimizuka...
Well, uh, you know...
I feel like once I say this,
I'll never escape it, but...
I'm used to girls being mean to me!
What? Why are you
sharing your fetish now?
Hey, I'm trying to make you feel better!
You're cheering me up by confessing
that you're a masochist?
That's crazy.
You're more messed up than I thought!
I was kidding...
I just wanted to make you laugh...
It's not actually my fetish...
You're so dumb.
You really are so dumb.
Which of us is?
You've been holding it in for so long.
Now that you've stopped crying,
let's start talking about that "mistake"
Noches was referring to.
Do you have any ideas?
No, none.
When Siesta was alive,
she said that "past" was the truth.
But something in it was wrong.
Which means that when she was alive,
Siesta made a mistake, maybe?
But would Siesta-san make a mistake?
True...
Maybe it's fastest to talk
to the people involved?
There's me and Siesta, then you. Who else?
Char... But if she didn't say anything then,
nothing must've occurred to her.
Maybe our enemies, then?
SPES, huh?
But then how would we talk to them?
Hel.
But Siesta sealed Hel away inside me, right?
We're going to call her out?
But then she'll have
sealed her away for nothing—
One year.
She spent one year persuading her.
I'm sure it'll be okay.
But her...
I heard what you were saying.
If you're going to summon Hel,
please leave it to me.
So? Why are we in my house?
This was the closest place where it
seemed safe to make a lot of noise.
I didn't say anything about it
being okay to make a lot of noise...
Is it okay for a detective to ask
for help from a client, anyway?
You really are an idiot, Kimihiko.
Siesta-sama would have said
that it's okay to do anything to
protect your client's interests.
You're right.
Noches-san.
How can I meet Hel... the other me?
We'll summon her into that mirror.
Hold this.
And then stare at yourself in the mirror.
Mirrors facing each other?
There are sayings about
mirrors facing each other.
They say a pair of mirrors
can summon a devil.
That they can show
the past and the future.
It's not difficult.
If you wish to see her, the slightest
chance will bring Hel to you.
So just keep looking
at yourself in the mirror.
Natsunagi?
It's been a long time.
Master.
EPISODE 2:
A STORY OF THAT DAY NO ONE KNOWS